Experience & Interaction Designer

Hello, I am Federico, a digital product designer focus on user experience, user interface and interaction. I'm love also frontend development and photography. I have been creating digital design over past 3 years.

Enough talk. Show me more but less.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

User Experience & Interaction Designer

IT Value Partner, from September 2022

At IT Value Partner I work both on internal projects, such as the creation of a blockchain platform, and on external projects, working with Bitmama and Unicredit.

Co-founder

Fantapp, from May 2022

I participated in a startup pre-acceleration program organized by Bocconi University & Idea Booster Lab with Fantapp, an app dedicated to revolutionizing the world of fantasy games.

User Interface & Interaction Designer

Value Partners, from April 2021 to september 2022

At Value Partners I participated in various projects in the role of User Interface Designer, as well as User Experience & Interaction Designer. The clients I worked with included Juventus, UnipolSai, Zegna, Crif, Edison and OneofUs.

UX/UI Designer

Freelance, from July 2020 to April 2021

As a freelance I have collaborated with different brands, for example MemoriesNow, Sponsor.smart, Take eat easy, The Language Grid, Dropshot and others, helping them to develop digital products with human-centered experiences and outstanding interfaces.

Visual & Brand Designer

Value Partners, from April 2021 to september 2022

As a freelance I have collaborated with different brands, for example OpenBeach Milano, Evodia, Gianluca Rossi Party&Events, Children in Crisis and others, helping them to develop coordinated visual&communication campaigns and digital content.

Visual & Web Designer

Freelance, from May 2019 to April 2021

At Liligutt I designed graphic concepts and web contents for Linda Meyer Henschel website.

EDUCATION

Workshop Light Verona

Politecnico di Milano, from April 2020 to May 2020

Urban installations of light for a city to be relaunched from a tourist point of view.

Interior design bachelor degree

Politecnico di Milano, from Semptember 2017 to July 2020

Thesis title: Otto e mezzo nello sguardo di Paul Ronald.

High school diploma

Liceo Scientifico Elio Vittorini, from Semptember 2012 to July 2017

Scientific high school diploma.

Gamification - How to Create Engaging User Experiences

The Interaction Design Foundation, August 2022

Agile Methods for UX Design

The Interaction Design Foundation, August 2022

Design for the 21st Century with Don Norman

The Interaction Design Foundation, August 2022

Journey Mapping

The Interaction Design Foundation, August 2022

Service Design: How to Design Integrated Service Experiences

The Interaction Design Foundation, August 2022

User Experience: The Beginner's Guide

The Interaction Design Foundation, August 2022

Idea Booster Lab Program

Idea Booster Lab, May 2022

Training program designed to improve the entrepreneurial skills of early stage startups and newly founded companies.

Next.js & React

Udemy, April 2022

Frontend Next.js and React technologies course.

Toeic B2

Eas Milano, August 2020

Test of english for international communication, level B2.

AWARDS

Top 10 teams

Reply Creative Challenge 2022, June 2022

Recognized as one of the 10 best team in the Customer Experience category of the Reply Creative Challenge, with 962 participating teams.